Markus Unger SOFTWARE ENGINEER



Markus Unger Triftweg 59, 04227 Leipzig Germany markus@unger.dev www.unger.dev +49 176 63156390

PROFILE

I am a software engineer with experience in building RESTful backend services and rich frontend applications in JavaScript and Ruby, leveraging both SQL and NoSQL data stores as well as frameworks like React. Previously, I worked in book design and typesetting and have strong typographic knowledge.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, 200 OK

(January 2020 – May 2020)

- ▶ Created an open-source backend service for ephemeral REST APIs with Node.js/Express, MongoDB, Redis and HTML/CSS/React (https://200ok.app)
- ▶ Designed a multi-tenant REST interface application with support for schemaless, no-configuration data storage
- ▶ Used message broker and Server-sent events for real-time communication between server applications and browser clients
- ▶ Managed the complete development cycle from application design to deployment
- ▶ Author of an extensive user documentation (https://200ok.app/documentation) as well as a detailed technical case study (https://200ok.app/case-study)

Self-Employed

(2018 - 2019)

- ▷ Developed open-source applications with various technologies, including JavaScript, Node.js, Ruby, React, PostgreSQL
- ▶ A Dungeon Forgotten: a procedurally generated game in Ruby and Sinatra with a HTML/CSS/JavaScript interface
- ▷ NodeHue: a JavaScript/Node.js control application for Philips Hue smart lights

Book Publishing Staff, Sax-Verlag

(2008 - 2019)

- > Introduced several digital tools for CRM and automated production as well as writing automation scripts
- ▶ Responsible for metadata management, internal digital production workflows and employer training for digital technologies
- ▶ Typesetting and design for 100+ scientific and other non-fictional publications (Adobe InDesign)
- ▷ Design and layout work for book covers, illustrations and advertisement in both print and web format

SKILLS

JavaScript (including ES6), Ruby, Node.js, Express, React, Sinatra, SQL, MongoDB, Redis, Docker, REST API design, HTML, CSS

EDUCATION

Launch School

(2018 - 2019)

Multi-year full-stack software engineering curriculum with focus on (web) development fundamentals, problem solving and algorithmic thinking

University Of Applied Sciences (HTWK) Leipzig

(2003 - 2008)

Diplom-Ingenieur (graduated engineer) Medientechnik (media technology)